Episode 12
And The One She Chooses Is
A being that can kill me?
Perhaps that was true.
Maybe I did long for that for a time.
Mio.
It's not a lie that I was
trying to resurrect Shin.
I have kept on living
so I could see Shin one more time.
But as you said:
"Is the man I gave birth to truly Shin?"
That doubt lingered in part of my mind.
Though I had no idea
what else I was supposed to do.
I see.
Perhaps I truly did want to die all this time.
How did I never realize
something so simple before?
If you came to kiss me
while understanding all of that,
then that means
you intend to kill me, doesn't it?
Yes.
Is that what you thought I'd say?
Huh?
Sorry, but I don't have the nerves
of steel you've shown.
I'm not going to shoulder
the burden of your death.
You see, Mio,
I came here to steal you away from Shinji!
Right now all ten sephirah reside within me.
I can probably seal away
your Spirit power as well.
But sealing you shouldn't equal death.
Not as long as you don't choose death yourself.
So with that...
Forget about your old love
and come hook up with me, Mio.
What was that?
That doesn't suit you at all, Shido.
Are you even being serious?
S-Setting aside whether that suited me or not!
I'm serious!
I genuinely intend to
steal you away from Shinji!
I see.
That's what he says,
but what do you think, Shin?
Am I allowed to say something here?
I'm just something separated
from Shido's memories.
I'm basically an imitation of an imitation?
But your memories are those of Shin's, right?
So speak.
Whatever you're thinking should be
the same as what the real Shinji would.
Otherwise, I might just get
stolen away by Shido, you know?
Is that so?
In that case, I will speak my mind.
Screw you, bastard!
O-Oh?!
You keep saying whatever you
damn well please while I hold my tongue!
But even I can't forgive you for this!
I'm never handing Mio over to you!
So yeah, that's how I would feel
were I still alive.
Though...
I don't exist anymore, right?
Honestly, the thought of Mio
choosing anyone other than me
makes my heart feel like it'll burst.
But even so, I don't want Mio
to choose death either.
There were still so many things
in this world that I wanted to show Mio.
This ocean is pretty.
I'm really glad I got to bring Mio here.
But
it's about time she visits somewhere else, too.
I'm sorry, Mio.
I've kept you tied down for far too long.
Mio.
Shido, I...
Wh-What?!
Reine, is this?!
Interference from outside.
It's most likely the Spirit Formula.
Spirit Formula?
The formula once used to create
a Spirit, meaning me, in this world.
It's a secret magic ritual.
As far as I know, the only one
capable of activating it is Westcott.
Hold on a minute!
Are you saying they're trying
to give birth to a new Spirit outside?
It would seem so.
He wants another Spirit of Origin like me.
And this time it looks like Westcott
is at the center of that power.
Apparently he's trying to use himself
as a core while activating it.
You mean Westcott is trying to
gain the power of a Spirit of Origin?!
The same level of power Mio wields?!
Yes.
A massive flow of Spirit Power
is already gathered here in me.
Westcott intends to use this flow
to make himself a Spirit of Origin.
He doesn't even need all ten sephirah anymore,
since he can just use the power
manifested here as-is.
Maybe that's what Westcott
was planning from the beginning?
Most likely.
He probably knew about
the situation ahead of time.
Because of me?
He was able to learn about what
I experienced in the future through Beelzebub.
No, if anything is responsible
for causing this, then that's me.
Besides, we don't have time to be
regretting things right now, right?
That's right.
I refuse to be used by that man,
and letting him overwrite the world that holds
my memories with Shin would be even worse.
Shido, lend me your power.
I know this might sound strange coming from me
after I killed all the Spirits in the future,
but let's go save everyone!
Yeah!
Shin.
Yeah.
I'll be going.
Mhmm, take care.
Shido.
Huh?
Uhh, then pardon me.
Thank you for the ultimate date.
Reine...
I know you'll be okay.
Now, let's go.
Yeah!
Shido!
Boy!
Darling!
Shido!
Master!
Brother!
Shido!
Sorry for the wait, everyone!
Hey, Isaac Westcott.
It looks like you've really had your way
with things while we were gone.
I'm grateful to you, Shido Itsuka.
After all, you're the one who kept
Deus in place while I activated my formula.
Belial!
Belial?!
It's a Demon King.
One with power on par with Mio's Angel.
Shido, that's!
He's planning to fundamentally
rewrite this world!
Mio?
Ein Sof.
Mio!
I can't hold this for long!
Everyone, please, lend me your power!
So I can protect this world where I met Shin!
What's this?
Oh! Is this—?!
Still, we're up against another Spirit.
We'll need to coalesce everyone's
power in order to fully defeat him.
Coalesce our power?
Can you do that?
He's right here, isn't he?
The one man who can
wield the power of all the Angels.
Here we go, everyone!
To save the world!
You think I'd let you?!
We won't let you through!
Belial!
Gabriel!
Use this power as well!
Zaphkiel, Aleph!
Halvanhelv!
Michael, Siffleur!
Camael!
Not bad.
How about this, then?
Athiel!
That's!
Huh?
Don't worry!
You can rest easy
now that I'm back in business!
Well done, Nia.
I've raised your usefulness rating
from paramecium to water flea.
That voice?
Are you Maria?
Yes. I've obtained my long-awaited real body,
and now I'm the perfect Maria.
Nibeelcole was a pseudo-Spirit
created by Beelzebub.
So there's no reason
the same couldn't be done with Raziel.
Of course, the individual units
hit with Athiel's power can't be resurrected,
but it's possible for me
to protect you all with this body,
even if only for a brief time.
Go, Maria!
I choose you!
Maria won't obey.
Ow!
Now, leave your defense to me and go, Shido.
Go put an end to this.
Yeah!
Metatron!
Raziel!
Zaphkiel!
Zadkiel!
Camael!
Michael!
Haniel!
Raphael!
Gabriel!
Sandalphon!
Go, Shido!
Yeah!
Shido Itsuka!
Splendidly done, Shido Itsuka.
But you were one step shy.
What?!
Qemetiel!
Shido!
Boy!
Master!
Darling!
Brother!
Shido!
You can't, Shido.
Mio!
You have all those girls waiting for you.
His Spirit Power is out of control.
If we leave that alone,
it'll blow away the entire world.
But if I use my Ein to cancel it out,
then I might be able to stop it.
Wha?!
But if you do that, then you'll—!
Even Shinji said it to you, didn't he?!
He wanted you to see more of this world!
So why would you—?!
Shido, you really are wonderful.
I do love you.
Just second to Shinji, you know?
Mio!
Deus, huh?
What a luxury to have you watch over my death.
I'm sure we don't belong in the world to come.
Neither you nor I.
I wonder why I was never able to obtain you.
You should never have created
a Spirit in the first place.
This power is too much for mankind.
Though, well, yes...
if there were some misfortune
in addition to that...
then it would be that you weren't my type.
I see.
Nothing I could do about that, huh?
Qemetiel.
Ein.
This was for the best.
I was too late in realizing it,
but at least I managed to protect Shido
and everyone else in the end.
I'm sorry, everyone.
Mio.
I'm sorry, Mio.
I've kept you waiting for an awfully long time.
Shin!
Shin! Shin!
Mio!
I've missed you for so, so long!
I've missed you for so long, too!
From now on, we'll be together forever!
Yeah!
Ike!
Hey, Ellen.
Ike, look at what's happened to you!
We need to get you into
a medical realizer quick!
It's no use.
I got caught up in an Angel and a Demon King
canceling each other out at close range.
It's a miracle I'm even still conscious.
Ike...
Hey, Elliot.
Karen, too.
Please, Elliot! Save Ike!
You can do it, can't you?!
Elliot...
I would if I could.
But he's already...
So what brought you all the way here?
Did you come to laugh at me?
Is it that strange that I would want
to see my friend when he's dying?
Yeah, that was a mean question.
Even though our paths differed,
you and Karen were still my friends.
Besides,
we're also two men
rejected by the same woman.
That's certainly true.
What? It was this easy to obtain?
Shido! Shido!
Shido!
You're awake?
We were worried about you.
Relief. Kaguya was so fraught with worry
she was weeping as she clung to you.
I never went that far!
Tohka, where's Mio?
I see.
Ahh, she rejected me in the end.
Said she preferred Shin over me.
I see.
Nothing we can do about that then.
I suppose this means even you weren't
a match for that pure-love couple.
Huh?
You finally got to see Shin, huh Mio?
Shido!
Sorry I'm late, Shido.
I only just got here myself.
Now, Shido,
let's enjoy our date!